Majid Saberi

I am a computational neuroscientist specializing in the analysis of neuroimages. My educational background is in physics, and I possess expertise in statistical and computational methodologies. In addition to my conceptual perspective, I am enthusiastic about utilizing my well-honed techniques to investigate cognitive and brain mechanisms, especially at the network level.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+16478780739

WEBPAGE:

www.linkedin.com/in/majidsaberi/ www.github.com/majidsaberi/

EMAIL:

majidsaberi048@gmail.com

SKILLS

Neuroimage Analysis (sMRI, fMRI, DWI) Data Analysis and Biostatistics (R) Programming (R, Python, Shell, MATLAB) Machine Learning Graph Theory Linux System Administration

INTERESTS

Cognitive Functions Neural Disorders Brain Networks Brain Connectivity Complex Networks

REFERENCES:

Dr. Ali Khatibi ali.khatibi@gmail.com
Dr. Benjamin Dunkley
ben.dunkley@sickkids.ca
Dr. Gholamreza Jafari
g_jafari@sbu.ac.ir
Dr. Bratislav Misic
bratislav.misic@mcgill.ca
Dr. Reza Khosrowabadi
r_khosroabadi@sbu.ac.ir

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Fellow 2023 - now

The Hospital for Sick Children

Description: Developing biomarker for chronic pain and mental health challenges in PTSD

Supervisor: Dr. Benjamin Dunkley

Postdoctoral Fellow 2022 - 2023

University of Toronto

Description: Pain recovery signature based on neuroimaging data

Supervisor: Dr. Massieh Moayedi

Computational Specialist

2020 - 2022

National Brain Mapping Laboratory

Description: Setting-up, developing, and providing HPC services for local neuroscientists

Research Assistant 2013 - 2017

IPM, School of Cognitive Science

Description: Neural level olfactory coding Supervisor: Dr. Hamed Seyed-allaei

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Cognitive Science 2015 - 2021

Shahid Beheshti University

Thesis: Balance alteration of functional brain networks over the lifespan

Supervisors: Dr. Gholamreza Jafari, Dr. Reza Khosrowabadi

Advisors: Dr. Ali Khatibi, Dr. Bratislav Misic

M.Sc in Solid State Physics 2012 - 2014

K.N.Toosi University of Technology

B.Sc in Physics 2007 - 2012

K.N.Toosi University of Technology

PUBLICATIONS

Saberi, M., Khosrowabadi, R., Khatibi, A., Misic, B., & Jafari, G. (2022). **Pattern of frustration formation in the functional brain network**. *Network Neuroscience*, *6*(4), 1334-1356.

Saberi, M., Khosrowabadi, R., Khatibi, A., Misic, B., & Jafari, G. (2021). **Topological impact of negative links on the stability of resting-state brain network.** *Scientific reports*, 11(1), 1-14.

Saberi, M., Khosrowabadi, R., Khatibi, A., Misic, B., & Jafari, G. (2021). Requirement to change of functional brain network across the lifespan. *PloS one*, 16(11), e0260091.

Saberi, M., & Seyed-Allaei, H. (2016). Odorant receptors of Drosophila are sensitive to the molecular volume of odorants. *Scientific reports*, 6(1), 1-11.

CONFERENCE PRESENTATION

Neuroimaging datasets, studies and collaborations comprising Iranian populations: Current challenges and opportunities

Annual Meeting of the Organization for Human Brain Mapping, Montreal, 2023

Balance of resting-state functional networks

International Conference of Cognitive Science, Tehran, 2020

Assessing requirement to change the resting-state networks throughout lifespan stages (selected as the best oral presentation)

7th Iranian Human Brain Mapping Congress, Tehran, 2020

Olfactory receptors are sensitive to molecular volume

Conference on Frontiers in Olfaction, Triste, 2017

Functional areas of the brain have intrinsic temporal variabilities

3th Iranian Human Brian Mapping Congress, Tehran, 2016

SERVICES

Public affairs to boost international collaborations of Iran's neuroimaging community Providing network profiles of healthy development brains

Figshare Public Data Project, 2021

Organizing student challenge of age prediction based on morphological features of MRI images National Brain Mapping Laboratory, 2020

Organizing workshop on High-Performance Computing in neuroscience

National Brain Mapping Laboratory, 2019

Organizing hands on statistics with R, applied methods in cognitive science

IPM, School of Cognitive Science, 2017